原视频地址：youtu.be/50-QVbaIdbM
根据美国著作法(Copyright Law Revision)：
美国政府作品，由美国政府官员和雇员
作为其公务的一部分而编写的作品，不受著作法保护
（17 U.S. Code § 105）可在未经许可的情况下使用
视频中的内容和字幕均可二次创作，
但是原作者不对二次创作内容承担任何责任
本视频与字幕许可为CC BY-NC-SA 4.0
(署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享4.0 国际)协议
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
00:10处为正片
It began here at the Kennedy Space Center Florida last summer.
这一切开始于去年夏天的佛罗里达州肯尼迪航天中心
A pair of spacecraft Viking 1 and Viking 2 were readied for their separate journeys to Mars.
那时 海盗1号和海盗2号航天器已经准备好分别前往火星
Each is really two spacecraft in one.
(实际上) 海盗号的每个航天器都由两个航天器组成
A 5,000 pound orbiter with cameras and communications gear
一个带有相机和通讯设备 重达2.268吨的轨道器
and sealed inside to saucer-like capsules at the other end, the Viking landing craft.
并将其封盖在另一端的碟状舱 海盗号着陆舱外
A camera equipped automated biological and chemistry laboratory and seismic station
着陆舱上装有相机 自动化生物和化学实验室 以及地震台
which has been purged of Earthly organisms by being heated in a huge oven.
而通过在一个巨大的炉子里加热的方法 已经清除了这些航天器上携带的地球生物
The 11-month, 420-million-mile trip for the two Viking orbiter Landers was set in motion by two launches.
通过两次对两艘海盗号轨道器和着陆器的发射 将启动为期11个月 6.8亿公里的行程
均使用Titan IIIE火箭发射
One in August. One in September.
两次发射分别发生在8月和9月
Earth shrinks smaller and smaller as the two Vikings head toward their Martian rendezvous.
当两艘海盗号在与火星交会时 其视野内的地球将越变越小
Then, braking rockets fire on command,
(在交会时) 制动火箭将按指令点火
slowing the first Viking Explorer enough that it goes into orbit around Mars.
减慢第一艘海盗号探测器的速度 使其足以进入绕火轨道
For the next two weeks, the orbiting spacecraft will survey the surface below,
在开始绕火的两周内 轨道器将勘测下方的火星地表
transmitting pictures of possible landing sites to scientists on Earth.
向地球上的科学家发送可能的着陆地点的照片
The Martian surface should be a study in contrasts.
对火星表面的研究会涉及到对比
From vast dust swept plains to immense canyons and frost covered plateaus,
火星的地形 既有尘土飞扬的广阔平原 也有巨大的峡谷和覆盖着冰霜的高原
huge gullies and channels photographed by earlier Mariner spacecraft
还有纵横的沟壑 这些都被之前的水手号航天器拍摄到了
are believed to have been caused by running water sometime in the distant past.
据信是由远古时期的流水造成的
If all goes as planned,
如果一切按计划进行
the first Viking Lander will separate from the orbiting command ship and descend to the Martian surface.
第一艘海盗号着陆器将与轨道(指令)器分离 并下降到火星表面
实际上是在1976年7月20日着陆的
Landing at 9:40 p.m. Eastern Daylight Time July 4th.
在美国东部夏令时间7月4日晚上9点40分着陆
实际上是在1976年9月3日着陆的
The second Viking is scheduled to land on September 4th, 1000 miles to the northeast of Viking 1.
第二艘海盗号计划于9月4日 在海盗1号东北方向1609公里处着陆
How will Viking go about looking for life on Mars.
那么 海盗号将如何去寻找火星上的生命呢
We asked Dr. Richard Young, NASA's chief of planetary biology.
我们请教了NASA的行星生物学主管 理查德·杨博士
We look for life on Mars in much the same way we would look for life on Earth
我们在火星和在地球上寻找生命的方式是差不多的
if we were forced to use an automated device and we don't send a scientist along
如果我们被迫使用自动装置且不派科学家一起去找的话
if we were sending a little wagon out into the Sahara Desert
如果我们派一辆小马车到撒哈拉沙漠去的话
or one of the dry valleys of the Antarctic
或者是一段干燥的南极山谷
which had to function all by itself with automated equipment.
同时 这台设备还必须用自动化设备进行运作
this is probably exactly what we would sing.
而这很可能就和我们要做的一样
And let me say by the way that we're looking primarily for microorganisms.
让我顺便说一下 我们主要是在寻找微生物
It would be rather fruitless of us for to look for horses on Mars.
(因为)我们在火星上找马的话可能是徒劳的
We wouldn't look for horses on Earth if we were looking for life
就算是在地球上寻找生命 也不可能(一开始)就找马(这种大型生物)
because the chances would be median to one against finding them with a random search.
因为随便找找 就能找到的几率不高
Vikings mechanical arm pulls in a scoop full of Martian soil
海盗人的机械臂取出了满满一瓢火星土壤
and drops it into a one cubic foot box.
然后把火星土壤扔进一个30升的盒子里
That's really three completely automated testing laboratories.
这实际上是三个完全自动化的检测实验室
It is here that the possibilities for or against the presence of life will be determined.
在这里 生命存在与否的可能性将被确定
What will it mean to Earthlings if life is found on Mars.
那么 如果在火星上发现生命 对地球人意味着什么？
It must mean that the universe is literally an inhabited universe with many planets that have life on it.
这一定意味着宇宙是一个有别的生命存在的宇宙 其中许多星球上都有生命
杰拉尔德·A·索芬
海盗号项目科学家，兰利研究中心
Now if there are many planets that have life on it,
那么如果有许多星球上有生命
there is no doubt at all
毋庸置疑
that terrestrial life is not going to be the most advanced civilization, the most highest level of consciousness.
地球上的生命(可能)不会是最先进的文明 不具有最高层次的意识
We must be somewheres in the broad spectrum of possibility.
我们肯定是在广泛的(存在生命的)可能性范围内的某个位置上
And that drives you to the conclusion
这让你得出了一个结论
is that there may be conscious life elsewhere in the universe.
那么就是宇宙中其他的地方 可能存在有意识的生命
Vikings to Mars and the search for life there.
海盗号来到火星 并在那里寻找生命
This country's first close-up scientific exploration of the Red Planet.
这是这个国家对红色星球的第一次近距离科学探索